but listen to me Are you okay or what? Is
pero escúchame Estás bien o qué sí está
everything okay, let's see inside? I'm
todo bien a ver por dentro Estoy
totally devastated emotionally I'm
totalmente destrozado anímicamente estoy
fine but I'm very, very devastated I mean,
bien pero estoy muy muy destrozado O sea
I can act strong and I can say
me puedo hacer el fuerte y puedo decir
everything's okay like I always say but
está todo bien como digo siempre pero
inside I'm uh destroyed I can't say anything
por dentro estoy eh destrozado no puedo
else, I mean, ah I'm screwed
decir otra cosa es decir ah estoy [__]
I'm screwed but oh well, you have to keep going, you ca
estoy [__] pero bueno hay que seguir
n't stop You have to keep going You have to keep going You have to keep going, you ca
es que no puedes parar Hay que seguir
n't
Hay que seguir Hay que seguir no puedes
say that you have to put it aside and
decir hay que aparte lo para arriba y a
fight because this doesn't look like it's going to
pelear porque esto no tiene pinta de de
end anytime soon In fact, I would say that it's just
acabar pronto De hecho diría que está
starting but it's true
que está empezando pero sí que es verdad
that the other day, man, when
que el otro día tío cuando cuando pasó
everything happened, all of a sudden, I didn't expect it
todo de repente yo no me lo esperaba eh
at all, I don't know if you did have it.
para nada yo no sé si si tú sí tenías
Of course, this was going to happen before
Claro que esto iba a pasar antes de lo
Thursday, but I've been saying it for a
del jueves pero yo est yo llevo diciendo
while, eh jav, I've been saying it for a
tiempo eh jav yo lo llevo diciendo
while that they want to put me in jail, they
tiempo que quieren meter en la cárcel me
want to hurt me and I've been saying it for a
quieren hacer daño y lo llevo diciendo
while, what happens is that I didn't
tiempo lo que pasa es que yo no me
expect it to be like this, I didn't expect it, I
esperaba que fuera así no me lo esperaba
mean, the other day I suddenly said, I'm
es decir yo el otro día dije de repente
going to leave the sanctuary, I'm going to see if I can
voy a dejar el santuario voy a ver si
do something in Australia, so and so
hago algo en Australia tal y al día
next day just what happens happens No, I
siguiente justo pasa lo que pasa No yo
have a decision that I have made about
hay una decisión que he tomado de de
how I am going to maintain the sanctuary but
cómo voy a mantener el santuario pero
surely I will have to do it from
seguramente que lo tenga que hacer desde
outside of Thailand okay I did not
fuera de Tailandia de acuerdo Yo no me
expect this I expected bad things such
esperaba esto me esperaba mal cosas tal
attacks and But this is this is something that is
ataques e Pero esto es esto es algo que
not to hurt you it is to
es para no es para hacerte daño es para
destroy you And if they can either kill you with
destrozarte Y si pueden o matarte de
grief or kill you somewhere else in another
pena o matarte en otro sitio de otra
way I mean I am very
manera es decir a mí pelear se me da muy
good at fighting I am very good at fighting but they
bien luchar se me da muy bien pero me
are touching me on several fronts that
están tocando varios frentes que a mí me
hurt me a lot the issue of the animals
duele muchísimo el tema de los animales
hurts me a lot a lot and the
me duele muchísimo muchísimo y el tema
personal issue hurts me a lot I mean and
personal me duele muchísimo es decir y
seeing my children how they are that people will
ver a mis hijos cómo están que la gente
always say you say about your children it is that
dirá siempre dices de tus hijos es que
my life are my animals and my children that
mi vida son mis animales y mis hijos eso
is the only thing I have I mean it is what I have
es lo único que tengo es decir es lo que
okay eh And the rest Well it is
tengo vale eh Y el resto Pues bueno es
random but but that is what I have
aleatorio pero pero eso es por lo que he
fought for for many years and when you see
luchado durante muchos años y cuando ves
your children completely devastated
a tus hijos completamente destrozados
but destroyed but they keep going
pero destrozados pero que siguen para
look Imagine the five days
adelante mir Imagínate los cinco días
that he has had the fox and you have been
que ha tenido zorro y tú has estado
talking to him and it is brutal and and b jooy and
hablando con él y es brutal y y b jooy y
Paloma  the five days that they've had I
Paloma los cinco días que han tenido O
mean it's something that no one
sea que es algo que que no nadie se
can even imagine because
puede Ni imaginar porque se pueden decir
many things can be said but Paloma was here and she has
muchas cosas pero Paloma estaba aquí y
n't left and she was here the last time
no se ha ido y estaba aquí la última vez
the police came and she could have said
que vino la policía y podía haber dicho
Hey, I'm scared I'm leaving you know and
Oye a mí me da miedo Esto me voy sabes y
here she has stayed and here she has stayed
aquí se ha quedado y aquí se ha quedado
and the police were here and here
y estaba la policía aquí y aquí estaba
she was feeding the animals
ella dando de comer a los animales
so eh They've been tough days there are going to be
entonces eh Han sido días duros van a
very tough days very very very tough it
venir días Muy duros muy muy muy duros
probably won't be the last time I
seguramente no sea la última vez que
end up in a cell I'm probably
termino en un calabozo seguramente os lo
telling you now even worse because this is something
digo ya incluso peor porque esto es algo
that's been going on for a long time and it's something that
que viene de hace tiempo y es algo que
was thought out and programmed to
está pensado y programado para
destroy me there's a video of Diego
destrozarme hay un vídeo de Diego
Arrabal that I saw a while ago and I thanked him and
arrabal que me he visto hace un rato y
publicly not publicly
públicamente no públicamente
privately I sent him a message
privadamente le he mandado un mensaje
Look, Diego and I are fighting
Mira que con Diego andamos a hostias
every now and then because we are both
cada dos por tres porque somos los dos
equally brutal and stubborn no
igual de de brutos y de cabezones no
but anyway the important thing is Franco has been
pero bueno lo importante Franco est ha
released supposedly on
sido puesto en libertad se supone que
bail and now we'll see what
bajo fianza y ahora vamos a ver qué es
happens now we'll see what
lo que pasa ahora vamos a ver qué es lo
happens this yes  I have to explain
que pasa esto si yo tengo que explicar
this to me it smells a little a
esto a mí me huele que es un poco un
little strange a little strange it's like
poquito raro un poquito raro es como
this is going to happen a dita or two D in the
este va a pasar un dita o dos D en el
dungeon but of course I knew when
calaboso pero claro yo sabía cuando vino
Diego came when Diego came I
Diego cuando vino Diego yo
knew is that when Diego came here I
sabía es que cuando vino Diego aquí yo
already knew that I wasn't going to talk to my
ya sabía que no iba a hablar con con mi
family or my ex-family you know and one
familia o mi ex familia sabes y y una
thing to be thankful for is that he was a
cosa de agradecer es que haya sido
journalist and not a son of a [ __ ] You know
periodista y no hijo de [__] Sabes
because he could perfectly well tomorrow he
porque él podía perfectamente mañana
could take it and do pum you know Well he
podía [__] y hacer pum sabes Bueno lo
could have done it 50 months ago in fact
pudo haber hecho hace 5co meses de hecho
yes but he hasn't done it he's going very well
sí pero no lo ha hecho va muy bien
eh I saw his live yesterday and I
encaminado eh yo vi ayer su directo y y
say go go FL But ok Now
digo va va FL Pero bueno Ahora más
later we'll talk about that I don't know if you would
adelante hablamos de eso no sé si si te
like to explain a little bit How it happens
gustaría explicar un poquito Cómo sucede
suddenly that I don't know what time it was there
de repente ese no sé qué hora sería allí
I was here at the salsería no and
yo estaba aquí en la salsería no y de
suddenly you send me a message and it leaves me
repente me mandas un mensaje y me dejas
stunned no that it's like [ __ ] like
de piedra no que es como [__] como las
7:30 8 in the morning yeah around there and
7:30 8 de la mañana sí por ahí y de
suddenly I heard a drone up above right
repente escuché un dron arriba justo
above where I am now I went out
arriba de donde estoy yo ahora salí
I heard another drone further away I came I
escuché otro dron más alejado vine me
ran inside  I looked through the cameras and saw
metí corriendo miré por las cámaras y vi
that there were like 16 police cars and
que había como 16 coches de policía y de
assault vehicles and everything outside. I said, Holy crap, huh.
asalto y de todo fuera digo J hostias eh
And nothing, and I went out, they were outside, they told me
Y nada y salí estaban fuera me dijeron
we have a search warrant, it was in the
tenemos una orden de registro era de los
30s, there were eight people who had
30 y pico eran ocho personas que habían
come last time, okay, out of these 30s, there were
venido la última vez vale de estos 30 y
people from national parks
pico había gente de parques nacionales
that I've known for 20 years and nothing, they came in
que yo conozco hace 20 años y nada
and despite everything, they came in and despite everything,
entraron y con todo entraron y con todo
then they asked me, they said, Hey, hey, we
entonces me preguntaron dijeron Oye eh
came because there's a report that you have
venimos porque hay una denuncia eh de
animals here
que tienes aquí animales
and they don't have the papers, huh. And
e que no tienen los papeles eh Y
then automatically they no longer
entonces automáticamente ya no pasan a
become your property, let's say. In that
ser de tu propiedad digamos En ese
sense, they become illegal. Do you have
sentido pasan a ser ilegales tienes
any, of course? I told the policeman, I
alguno claro yo le dije al policía le
said, but man, were you here
dije pero macho si estuviste aquí la
last week? I don't know if you were referring to
semana pasada y no sé si te referías a
the otters, and he says, Oh, right, they're the otters, and I say,
las nutrias y dice Ah claro son las
[ __ ], it seems like this, he says you
nutrias y digo [__] parece esto dice
still have them here, and I say, sure, I
las tienes todavía aquí y digo claro les
took them where the little otters were,
llevé dónde estaban las nutrias pequeñas
the babies, he explained to me, he says, look, since
los bebés me explicó dice mira desde el
last year, which he could have also
año pasado que también me lo podía haber
told me the last time he was here. But anyway,
dicho la última vez que estuvo Pero
but since last year,
bueno pero desde el año pasado las
otters are not legal  have them in this
nutrias no son legales tenerlas en esta
here like this and I say look, I did
aquí que tal que cual y digo Mira yo es
n't know that last year at the end
que no sabía que el año pasado al final
of last year this law changed and I included
del año pasado cambió esta ley incluí
the otters of such and such, I say also
las nutrias de tal y cual digo además es
these otters you know where
que estas nutrias Tú sabes dónde de
where they come from it says yes but it's that you
dónde vienen dice ya pero es que las
have them here are illegal right now I say
tienes aquí son ilegales ahora mismo
[ __ ] well I search them or whatever it is he
digo [__] pues las registro o lo que
says no and I say well and I thought I say you
sea dice no y digo bueno y yo pensé digo
could have told me the last time you
me lo podías haber dicho la última vez
were here that you were
que estuviste aquí que las estuviste
seeing them and I was giving them bottles
viendo y estuve dándoles biberones
with you but let's see they are sent they
contigo pero a ver ellos son mandados
are police they come to do
ellos son policías ellos vienen para
their job they tell them go over
hacer su trabajo les dicen vete para
there and if they have to go 30 go 30 and if they
allá y si tienen que ir 30 van 30 y si
have to go 200 go 200 Of course it's
tienen que ir 200 Van 200 Claro está
clear when we entered where where everything that is
claro cuando entramos donde donde todo
the sanctuary I told them Hey don't
lo que es el santuario les dije Oye no
bring guns in here because I don't want you to
metáis pistolas aquí porque no quiero
bring guns with the animals
que metáis pistolas con los animales
because you can get nervous at any
porque os podéis poner nerviosos en un
given moment and pull out a gun and of course the
momento dado y sacar una pistola y claro
team member the
el del de equipo el del equipo de
intervention team told me if I leave the
intervención me dijo si yo dejo la
gun outside I'll commit a foul
pistola fuera a mí me meteng una falta
man or  be the only thing I can tell you
macho o sea lo único que te puedo decir
is that I'm not going to shoot a
es que no le voy a disparar un animal
[ __ ] animal, I mean, I don't have a complaint, you
[__] es decir yo queja no tengo me
understand, I mean, they didn't treat me badly, they didn't treat me
entiendes es decir ni ni me trataron mal
with contempt, they didn't
ni me trataron con desprecio ni me
treat me, they treated me the way they should
trataron me trataron como me tienen que
treat me. They came to do a job, they
tratar ellos venían a hacer un trabajo
took the otters, took the photos,
cogieron las nutrias hicieron las fotos
took the video and put it
sacaron el vídeo y lo pusieron por todos
everywhere and that's it. Okay, it's another
los lados y ya está Vale es una
intervention, but more cinematic.
intervención más pero más peliculera
Let's say that this time it's more
vamos a decir que en esta ocasión es más
cinematic because in fact when we arrived at
peliculera que de hecho cuando llegamos
the De Lauan police station,
a la a la estación de policía de de
of course they were freaking out. At the
lauan claro ellos flipaba En la estación
police station because we arrived. There I arrived
de policía Porque llegamos Allí llego yo
and said, but what have you done? And I said no, it's that I have
y dice pero qué has hecho y digo no que
otters. He said,
es que tengo nutrias dice ya si es que
yeah, everyone knows. I mean, I make
todo el mundo lo sabe O sea yo hago
videos, of all the videos, everyone sees
vídeos ha os todos los vídeos todos ven
everything. And of course, by law, they're right, they're right, it
todo y claro por ley tienen razón tienen
's a law that was changed last year at the
razón es una ley que el año pasado a
end of the year, that was put in,
final de año se cambió esa se metió se
the otter was included in the animal that you
incluyó la nutria en en animal que no
can only have in a center
puedes tener más que en un centro
specialized solely in otters, which
especializado únicamente en nutrias que
is where it is now. Okay, only
es donde está ahora prx vale solamente
otters. And well  Well, they did that and
nutrias y Y bueno pues hicieron eso y
of course it's a crime, it's a crime and
claro es un delito es un delito y ahí ya
everything is already on video. It's all such that they're going to
está todo en vídeo Está todo tal que van
say no. Well, nothing happens. Well,
a decir no Bueno pues no pasa nada Pues
not this time, since everything was recorded at
no esta vez como estaba todo grabado a
100%, everyone had cameras, everyone had
100% todos llevaban cámaras todos
such, well, they took me to the
llevaban tal los pues me llevaron a la
police station, they read me my rights and
comisaría me leyeron mis derechos y para
inside and inside. So the
dentro y para dentro Entonces al día
next day I declared and well, with the
siguiente declaré y y bueno con el
lawyer, we explained everything. If you're
abogado explicamos todo eh si eres
guilty of something, you're guilty, I mean,
culpable de algo eres culpable es decir
ignorance of the law doesn't exempt you
el desconocimiento de la ley no te exime
from breaking the law, you understand. So
de de incumplir me entiendes Entonces
my mistake is that I didn't find out that
fallo mío de que no me enteré que el año
last year at the end of the year, they included
pasado a final de año pues incluyeron
the otters in the state in which they
las nutrias en el estado en el cual
have to be specifically in a
tienen que estar específicamente en un
specialized center only for
centro eh especializado solamente para
the okay, right now they are there in
la vale que ahora mismo están ahí en en
chomb bur tomorrow. In fact, tomorrow I'm
chomb bur mañana De hecho mañana me me
going with Paloma to see Plexi and
voy con Paloma para para ver a plexi y
resolve a little problem that was left
resolver un problemilla que que quedó
here. And such. But I'll tell you about it
aquí Y tal Pero que ya lo contaré más
later, I'll make a video and if you want to go
adelante haré un vídeo y si quieres haos
live, I think it's known that they
un directo creo que se sabe que dejaron
left an otter here, yes. So
aquí dejaron aquí una nutria sí Entonces
tomorrow I'm going to talk to them and such.  I'm
mañana voy a hablar con ellos y tal y y
going to try, eh, that she is because she is
voy a intentar eh que esté porque está
sad, if I can take her
tristona que si la puedo llevar para
there, okay. I think that
allá vale Yo creo que de buena voluntad
they left one out of good will, I think, okay. I think they
ellos dejaron una creo vale Yo creo que
did it out of good will because
lo hicieron a buena voluntad porque todo
everyone knows what I do here,
el mundo sabe a lo que me dedico aquí
everyone knows that I am not
todo el mundo sabe que yo no estoy
harming animals and
haciendo daño a los animales y todo el
everyone watches my videos and it's obvious I don't
mundo ve mis vídeos y y es es obvio no
hide anything because there is nothing to
escondo nada porque no hay nada que
hide, okay, but these people, a lot of
esconder vale pero esta gente mucha
people came from Bangkok, they didn't know me,
gente venía de Bangkok no me conocían
especially the ones who are police officers
sobre todo los que son policías policías
there, like, eh, like the geos, okay. And of
ahí en plan eh Como los geos vale Y
course, they came to look for things,
claro ellos venían a buscar cosas
specifically the weapons that are there, okay, they
específicamente las armas que hay vale
were checking if everything was in
estuvieron mirando si estaba todo en
order, if everything could be okay, eh,
reglas si podía estar todo bien eh
everything was okay there, Diego gave
estaba todo bien que ahí Diego ha dado
the key. Diego gave it. Totally, he didn't say, he did
la clave Diego ha dado Total no ha dicho
n't say weapons or anything. But he gave
no ha dicho armas ni nada Pero ha dado
the key and thank God, eh, he said. It's
la clave y gracias a Dios eh dijo Es que
there. Look at it, look at it and. And if there is a
está ahí Mírala míralo y Y si hay un
problem, tell me. They looked at it and saw
problema me lo dices lo miraron y vieron
that there was no problem. Okay, and nothing,
que no había ningún problema Vale y nada
and that's it. Well, another night in the
y ya fue Pues eso otra noche en el
cell because the next day I had to
calabozo porque al día siguiente tenía
go to court. I went to court.  I
que ir al al juzgado fui al juzgado me
opened with the judge, I set bail, they
abé con la jueza me puse una fianza me
could have sent me to jail until the
podía haber mandado a la cárcel hasta el
trial, which will be in April, I set
juicio que será en abril me puse una
bail so I could get out, and I'm
fianza e para poder salir y estoy estoy
out, but of course when you put up
fuera pero claro cuando te das una
bail here you have to leave your
fianza aquí tienes que dejar tu
passport, I mean, I can't travel, I
pasaporte es decir yo no puedo viajar no
can't escape, I wasn't going to
me puedo escapar tampoco me iba a
escape either, do you understand? I mean, when I
escapar me entiendes o sea yo cuando
said I was going to leave the sanctuary, it
dije que me iba a ir del santuario no
wasn't that I was going to escape tomorrow to the other
era que me iba a escapar mañana al otro
side. I think that could have been
lado yo creo que eso se ha podido
misinterpreted, eh, and when they
malinterpretar eh y cuando se han
met someone directly from you or they
encontrado con un directo tuyo o se los
sent them, it could also have had to do with
han mandado también ha podido tener que
whether they've warned them, they've warned them, they've warned them.
ver sí les han avisado les han avisado
Listen to me, what's he
han avisado escúchame que te está
telling you? That's p clb, I think that
diciendo que se p clb yo creo que eso
also affected them, they've warned them and that's why it's
también afectado les han avisado y por
accelerated, they've warned them. Yes, yes,
eso es aceleró les han avisado e Sí sí
because I can confirm it, I can confirm it, they've
porque te lo confirmo yo que me lo
warned them, but let's see, the
confirmas les han avisado pero a ver lo
messed up thing here is that I saw the animals
[__] aquí es que yo vi a los animales
so scared,
tan sumamente asustados ha explicado
Paloma explained what happened with the
Paloma lo que ha pasado con el loro
green parrot that won't leave me, that is, it
verde que no se separa de mí que es que
gets into my car  You know you see the
se me mete en el coche sabes Se ven el
police video there are the 30 guys
vídeo de la policía están los 30 tíos
chasing you while you are
persiguiéndote mientras que tú le estás
showing him the sanctuary and the parrot is
enseñando el santuario y el loro va
chasing you
detrás tuyo
that moment when they take to when they
ese momento cuando se llevan a cuando se
take to plexi Oh yeah God man and and
llevan a plexi Ah pues sí Dios tío y y
the other one stays here then I am she is
se queda la otra aquí entonces estoy
inside she is sitting there she is
está ahí dentro está ahí sentada está
inside my office because it makes me sad and
dentro de mi oficina porque me da pena y
above all the suffering of seeing
sobre todo el sufrimiento de de ver a
your children macho what is that eh zap is
tus hijos macho que es que eh zap está
in Spain and he is alone zorro is here
en España y lo pasa solo zorro está aquí
and Zorro is like me zorro is a problem a
y Zorro es como yo zorro es un problema
solution a problem a solution is
una solución un problema una solución es
just like me it hurts me all that you
igual que yo a mí me duele todo eso
know the nonsense of who is it What do they do How about it
sabes las tonterías de quién es Qué
hurts you but but for me
hacen Qué tal te duele pero pero para mí
The important thing is what I tell you the people
Lo importante es lo que te digo la gente
that I love the people that I care about and
que yo quiero la gente que me preocupa y
above all the stress that the
sobre todo el estrés que tuvieron las
animals were under that day is that there are a lot of
animales ese día es que son un montón de
people walking around the sanctuary
personas andando por el santuario
Looking here looking there
Mirando por aquí mirando por allá
lifting uh things to see here all
levantando eh cosas para ver aquí todos
the crates I tell you at no
los cajones que te digo en ningún
time did I feel danger or fear
momento ni sentí peligro ni sentí miedo
or eh pressure you know I mean at
ni sentí eh presión sabes es decir en
no time and there were 30 or so people
ningún momento y eran 30 y pico personas
eh I mean  I because of my character the first thing you
eh o sea yo por mi carácter lo primero
say boo boo What's up hands up and they
que dices bu bu Qué pasa manos arriba y
said to me Well they started explaining and
me dijeron Bueno empezaron a explicar y
I didn't feel any of that eh And then at the
yo no sentí nada de eso eh Y luego en la
police station here we
comisaría de policía aquí nos conocemos
all know each other I mean there are a lot of
todos es decir es que hay muchos
police officers who have come with the children
policías que han venido con los niños
here to see the otters or to see an
aquí para ver las nutrias o para ver un
abru for the first time or there are many Okay
abru por primera vez o hay muchos Vale
regional police chief came eh It
jefe de la policía regional vino eh No
's not that problem from here too I
es ese problema desde aquí también
want to thank the exiled prosecutor
Quiero agradecer a a exiliado fiscal
okay What he came to see me he lives
vale Alo que que vino a verme él vive
very close to here he came to see me he spent
muy cerca de aquí vino a verme estuvo
the two days coming and going to see me he
los dos días yendo y viniendo a verme me
called me when When you left he called me
llamó cuando Cuando saliste me llamó
because there was like a confusion with the
porque hubo como una confusión con el
issue that someone thought he was there he
tema de que alguien se pensó que había
thought there he thought it was the
se pensó aoy se pensó que
other one and then then pó and he
era el otro y entonces luego pó y me
said Hey tell your friend I'm sorry because I
dijo Oye dile a tu amigo Que perdone que
thought it was him but it's the
es que creí que era él pero es que es el
other one It's just slipped my mind and
otro Es que se me ha ido de la cabeza y
the kid called me as soon as you left
me llamó el chaval nada más que saliste
a short update came out like this
una actualización corta ha salido así
I suppose he's probably out on bail they have
Que supongo que habrá salido bajo fianza
n't let me talk to him
no me han dejado hablar con él
obviously because they expelled me from
obviamente porque me han expulsado de
there as if I were a journalist or
allí como si yo fuese un periodista o
something like that in fact there have
cualquier cosa de estas de hecho ha
been journalists who have recorded him
habido periodistas que lo han grabado
leaving who have recorded the car
saliendo que han grabado el coche
leaving and so on I wasn't there I
saliendo y demás yo no estaba allí yo no
wasn't there I suppose he saw
estaba allí Supongo que me habrá visto
that I wasn't there and if not they can
que yo no estaba allí y si no le pueden
ask the woman who was here
preguntar ar a la mujer que había aquí
from the courts Who recorded and who did
de los juzgados Quién ha grabado y quién
n't record So let's see if
no ha grabado Así que a ver si se aclara
this gets cleared up but anyway at least the good thing is
esto pero bueno por lo menos lo bueno es
that Fran has left So if he has left
que Fran ha salido Así que si ha salido
I imagine he's out on bail that
imagino que habrá salido bajo fianza
would be the most logical thing But the important thing
sería lo más lógico Pero lo importante
is that he's free because he
es que está en libertad porque me lo
told me so what's up is that I haven't sent him a
dijo lo pas que no le he mandado ni un
message or anything yet because I'm
mensaje ni nada todavía porque estoy
still crazy but a
todavía con la cabeza loca pero exiliado
fiscal exile who has been here for quite some time
fiscal que lleva aquí bastante tiempo
knows how all this works and if
sabe cómo funciona todo esto y si
anyone also wants to ask You here
alguien también quiere preguntar Tú aquí
went live with me too one
entró en directo conmigo también una
night Ah well he knows How it goes how
noche Ah pues él conoce Cómo va cómo va
this goes and he knows he knows what's behind it
esto y sabe sabe lo que hay detrás
too okay I don't know if no he didn't say it he didn't
también vale No s si no no lo dijo no lo
say it but he knows because he's also
dijo pero lo sabe porque él también está
very involved with the police and things and
muy involucrado con policía y cosas y
but he behaved very well Things have to be
pero se portó muy bien Hay que las cosas
said and and he behaved well
hay que decirlas y y él se portó bien
very well okay wine  here I didn't know him
muy bien vale vino aquí yo no lo conocía
when when he came out saying that he had
yo cuando cuando salió diciendo que
spoken to you in the cell I say
había hablado contigo en la celda digo
Fran shame and I begoña and I are fans
Fran vergoña y yo begoña y yo somos fans
of his but he said then tuyupa says that he
de él pero dijo luego tuyupa dice que
also knew him says I didn't know
también lo conocía dice yo no lo conocía
the boy we are big fans of but I already
al muchacho somos muy fans del pero ya
told you that in that sense I can't
te digo que en ese sentido no me puedo
complain I know that people speak very badly
quejar Yo sé que la gente habla muy mal
of the police maybe there is corruption but the
de la policía tal hay corrupción pero la
corruption is higher up the police
corrupción está más arriba los policías
behaved very well They have to
se portaron muy bien Ellos tienen que
do their job you understand I mean it's still
hacer su trabajo me entiendes O sea no
people who when they go
deja de ser personas que cuando se van a
home they have families too issue issue
casa tienen familias también tema tema
Zelda issue Zelda the conditions they have
Zelda tema Zelda las condiciones me han
told me that you have been well no I mean I
dicho que que has estado bien no O sea
say this so that people know that you have not been issue
lo digo para que la gente sepa que que
issue cell It's like
no has estado tema tema celda Es como
being like a Thai I mean it's a
estar como un tailandés o sea es es una
cell it's a cell I mean it's a
celda es un es una celda o sea es un
floor and a kind of panel and a
suelo y un una especie de panelito y un
hole in the floor to [ __ ] and that's what
agujero en el suelo para [__] y me es
the cell is let's see of course it's not a
lo que es la celda a ver claro no es un
hotel but they have behaved no there's
hotel pero que se han portado no no hay
nothing I mean there's nothing there's no bed there's no
nada O sea no hay nada no hay cama no
pillow there's nothing but it's it's
hay almohada no hay nada pero es que es
a Thai cell if you're in
es una celda tailandesa si estás en
Thailand you go to a Thai cell if you
Tailandia vas a una celda tailandesa si
are in Sweden I guess going to a
estás en Suecia Supongo que ira se una
Swedish cell is neither better nor worse it is what it is we
celda sueca no es ni mejor ni peor es lo
were all there the first
que hay todos estábamos allí el primer
day I was alone I mean the first day I
día estuve solo o sea el primer día
was alone second day there were three
estuve solo segundo día había tres
more kids there and such And well at
chavales más allí y tal Y bueno por lo
least you talk you know but but what it says
menos hablas sabes pero pero que dice
that t that they could bring you food they
que t que te podían llevar comida que te
could bring you your mattresses Cos s s yes they
podían llevar tus colchones Cos s s sí
took me LL corchon no your blanket or
me llevaron me LL corchon no tu manta o
something like that no yes yes they can take whatever you
algo de eso no sí sí te pueden llevar lo
want but but then of course you are
que quieras pero pero luego claro estás
there so you share it coke coffee I don't
ahí pues lo comparte coca-cola café no
know what I don't know how much in the end Well one
sé que no sé cuánto al final Pues un
kid gives this to the other the other I don't know
chaval le das esto al otro lo otro no sé
what And that's it but it is not what it is you can't
qué Y ya está pero no es es lo que es no
say how bad What the [ __ ] look
puedes decir que mal Qué [__] fíjate
what kind of it is not a place where not
qué tipo de no es un lugar donde todo el
everyone goes there so you can't say what a
mundo va ahí entonces no puedes decir
[ __ ] because that is what it is if you don't
vaya [__] porque es lo que hay si no
want to go to a cell in Thailand
quieres entrar a una centa en Tailandia
then don't live in Thailand or don't break
pues no vivas en Tailandia o no rompas
the law you know I mean but it
la ley sabes es decir pero a mí me nos
shocked us a lot because of course there in the end
impactó mucho porque claro allí al final
you say or no You don't have a tiger  you do
tú dices o no No tienes un tigre de
n't have any Bengals we're talking about
bengala no tienes estamos hablando de
otters no then of course first they
nutrias no entonces claro es que primero
lock you up and then they ask yes of
te te encierran y luego preguntan Sí
course the first thing they lock you up is that or rather
claro lo primero te cierran es que o sea
the first thing they lock you up and then you were the
lo primero te cierran y luego eras viene
lawyer comes you declare such and such I don't know what I don't know
el abogado declaras tal no sé qué no sé
how much here it works like that here first of
cuánto aquí funciona así aquí antes que
all they stop just in case and then hey
nada pues se paran por si acaso y luego
yes you haven't done anything they
ya Oye si si no has hecho nada pues te
let you go and say hey sorry we had to
sueltan y dicen oye perdona teníamos que
investigate that's it but it was clear
investigar ya está pero estaba Claro
because when they arrived here they already
porque yo cuando llegaron aquí ya me
told me hey he doesn't have the papers this is
dijeron Oye no tiene los papeles esto es
a crime of possession of Wildlife, that
un delito de posesión de de Vida Salvaje
is to say without permission which doesn't mean
es decir sin permiso que no quiere decir
that what I was fighting them for is hey but the thing is that these
que lo que yo les luchaba es Oye pero es
other two
que estas nutrias estas otras dos
otters the big ones have been here
nutrias las grandes llevan aquí más
longer than the law because the law if it
tiempo que la ley porque la ley si
starts at the end of last year it's in
empieza a final del año pasado está en
several years and they explained it to me and said okay
varios años y me lo explicaron y dijeron
but the thing is that you had to have
ya pero es que tenías que haber
registered everything I mean okay my fault that I did
registrado todo es decir vale fallo mío
n't realize that had changed that you
que no me enteré que había cambiado eso
know I can't find out about everything
sabes no me puedo enterar de de todo
better for you each animal comes to you in a
mejor a ti cada animal te llega de una
different way I mean suddenly
forma diferente o sea de repente te trae
a capricorn brings you And what do you have  that to do
una capí bara Y qué tienes que hacer
some kind of registration every time
algún tipo de registro cada vez que te
an animal comes to you every time
viene un animal cada vez que te viene
a snake comes to you there is a list there is a
una serpiente cada hay una lista hay una
list of animals that if they come to you
lista de animales que si te llegan los
you have to register them okay you have to
tienes que registrar vale tienes que
register it, I mean it will arrive tomorrow,
registrarlo es decir me llega mañana un
let's say another nutri will arrive that will
vamos a decir me llega otra nutri que me
arrive tomorrow, I have to say,
llegue mañana yo tengo que decir me ha
this otter has arrived okay, I will
llegado esta nutria de acuerdo la
register it, not an otter because now
registro no nutria porque ahora las
otters have to go to a
nutrias tienen que ir a un centro
specific center okay but but I receive, I don't know
específico vale pero pero me llega no sé
what to tell you, a vintur which is a
qué decirte un vintur que es un un oso
little bear here okay and I would have it as it
pequeñito aquí vale e yo tendría como
is on the list, I would have to call the
está en la lista yo tendría que llamar
national parks I mean,
al parques nacionales Es decir me ha
this animal has arrived I want to register that it
llegado este animal quiero registrar que
is here I will send you the photo I will send you the
está aquí te mando la foto te mando el
weight I will send you such eh I have it
peso te mando tal eh Te lo tengo
registered I have taken your blood or
registrado te he sacado sangre o te
the official veterinarian comes and takes
venga el veterinario oficial y le saque
the blood to have it and that's it and you have it
la sangre para tenerlo y ya está y lo
registered they give you the paper in that
tien registrado te dan el papel en ese
case I had the baby otters because they
caso yo tenía los bebés de nutria porque
were arriving 4 weeks ago two weeks ago
me iban llegando hace 4 semanas hace dos
and they were without papers I mean it's not
semanas y y estaban sin papeles O sea no
that they came and said that
es que hayan venido y hayan dicho que
son of a [ __ ] that I don't know what Look at what
hijo de [__] que no sé qué Fíjate lo que
you have, no It's that they came  because they had
tienes no Es que vinieron porque tenían
a complaint okay well Not a complaint
una denuncia vale bueno No una denuncia
because they already had it made but a resignation
porque tenían ya hecha pero una renuncia
to say surely this one is leaving tomorrow
para decir seguramente este se va mañana
from there take him and they did what they had to do let's
de ahí cogerlo y hicieron lo que tenían
see I do things wrong a lot of
que hacer a ver yo hago cosas mal muchas
times Javi I mean maybe I'm
veces Javi es decir a lo mejor esty
wanted maybe I'm very absent-minded eh I
desado a lo mejor soy muy despistado eh
know how I am I exaggerate things eh I
yo sé cómo soy yo exagero las cosas eh
tell you I have three candies and I tell you
Te digo tengo tres caramelos y te digo
that I have bu I have a lot of candies you're crazy I know you I
que tengo bu tengo una cantia caramelos
know you of course you
te flipas te conozco Te conozco claro me
understand that I am very very
entiendes que yo soy muy muy
exaggerated I of nonsense of these
exagerados yo de tonterías de estas
dead What's up but with the animal issue it
deado Qué tal pero con el tema animales
pisses me off because no I'm not going to say that I have
me jode porque no no voy a decir que he
sacrificed or I haven't sacrificed But
sacrificado o no he sacrificado Pero
because I put a lot I put a lot of
porque le pongo mucho Le pongo mucho
love into the animals and it worries me and And you
cariño a los animales y me preocupa y Y
know yesterday one of the cows
sabes ayer una de las de las vacas el
Ricky was there what about I don't know what stepped on
Ricky estaban ahí qué tal no sé qué pisó
a duck and killed it you know you have to yes
un pato y lo mató sabes tienes que sí
So yes things like that happen they happen no and it makes
Entonces sí pasan cosas así pasan no y
me very sad Well because you're with
me da mucha pena Pues porque estás con
them every day and and you can pick it up
ellos todos los días y y lo puedes [__]
you can throw it away and
lo puedes tirar por ahí está y que se lo
a bug can eat it but it makes you sad and you have
coma un [__] pero te da pena y tienes
to  take the shovel and you have to dig a
que [__] la pala y tienes que hacer un
hole and you know and you have to bury it
agujero y sabes y le tienes que enterrar
and and since I always do the same thing Well, you have to
y Y como siempre hago lo mismo Pues
go buy a little plant and
tienes que ir a comprar una plantita y
you have to put the little plant in because I
tienes que poner la plantita porque hago
always do the same thing and it pisses me off that
siempre lo mismo y me y me jode el hecho
the animals suffer I'm
de que los animales sufran yo estoy como
dying to go see Plexi tomorrow to
loco por ir a ver a plexi mañana para
know that I know that it's going to be okay because I
saber que sé que va a estar bien porque
know that center I know the people but
sé ese centro conozco a la gente pero
I want to go see it and I want to talk to the
quiero ir a verlo y quiero hablar con el
director where we went that the ran was
director donde fuimos que estaba la ran
the national park this is a
el parque nacionales esto es un centro
national center it's south it's almost 5 hours
nacional está al sur son casi 5 horas
from here and and we're going to go I'm going to talk
desde aquí y y vamos a ir voy a hablar
to the director there I'm going to tell him about
con el director allí le voy a decir el
this case and I'm going to tell him can I
caso de esta y le voy a decir puedo
bring Plexi to me I'm going to tell me it's that I
traerme plexi me voy a decir es que yo
know what he's going to tell me say look if it's
sé lo que me a decir a decir mira si es
in a month we could go look but I do
en un mes podríamos ir mirando pero es
n't have time um um you're going to be really
que no me da tiempo est est t ú está
sad in two days really sad that she's not
tristísima en dos días tristísima que no
eating and I'm going to tell him I have to bring the
come y le voy a decir tengo que traer la
other one and he's going to tell me yes no he's going to
otra y me va a decir que sí no me va a
tell me no maybe tomorrow I'll look at it and if it's
decir que no puces mañana lo miro y si
okay the day after tomorrow I'll take it  again
está bien pasado mañana me cojo otra vez
the car and we leave and we leave
el coche y nos vamos y dejamos a a
Dalsey there and that's it e but I already tell you
dalsey allí y ya está e pero ya te digo
to m to me but forever or or in the
a m a mí pero para siempre o o de
meantime Yes yes because they do the same thing they
mientras Sí sí porque hacen lo mismo
make families and when they have a
hacen familias y cuando tiene una
very complete family they let them loose
familia bien completa las dejan sueltas
and such I mean I think it's going to be
y tal es decir yo creo que va a estar
okay I have to see it tomorrow but I think it's
bien tengo que verlo mañana peroo creo
going to be okay it broke uh the
que va a estar bien se rompió eh la
photograph of plexi in the classrooms and
fotografía de de plexi en las aulas y
besides not the photos in the classrooms it's that of
aparte no las fotos en las aulas es que
course people who don't know it but
claro la gente quien no lo conozca pero
plexi when people arrive at the sanctuary
plexi cuando llega gente al santuario
always come with their
siempre viene con su
controversy he hugs you I don't know
polémica se te abraza no sé
what look look at the
qué mira mira el
little noise and he hugged the policeman many
ruidito y se abrazó al policía mucha
people haven't seen but he hugs the policeman his
gente no ha visto pero se abraza policí
leg and of course look at you the stick that I
la pierna y claro fíjate tú el palo que
know the stick that he takes to m that left me
se el palo que se lleva a m eso me dejó
but to m to me that hurts me a lot it
pero a m a mí eso me duele mucho me
hurts me to see what I'm telling you my
duele ver a lo que te digo a mis hijos
screwed children zape is very screwed very screwed
jodidos zape está muy [__] muy [__]
screwed I don't know if you've spoken to him these
[__] no sé si has hablado con él estos
days he's screwed [ __ ] zap zape he's been up
días está [__] jod zap zape ha echado
all night he's [ __ ]
todas las noches despierto está hecho
up and  Zorro what I'm telling you is like me
[__] y Zorro lo que te digo es como yo
and go ahead go and Paloma
y tira para delante tira y Paloma
imagine the state of nerves I
imagínate el estado de nervios en el que
was in because they also asked
estaba porque es que también preguntaron
Hey passport this I don't know what I don't know
Oye pasaporte esto no sé qué no sé
how much here they came for me lacia sonar
cuánto aquí venían a por mí lacia sonar
towards me and and they come and do their
hacia mí e y ellos vienen y hacen su
job I mean there's corruption for
trabajo Es decir que hay corrupción pues
sure and up and down and
seguro y arriba y abajo y en todos los
everywhere but they've treated me like
lados pero a mí me han tratado pues como
anyone else okay No more cocky no
a cualquiera vale No ni más chulo ni
less cocky or anything Everything's fine everything's well
menos chulo ni nada Todo bien todo bien
explained and I have no complaints in
explicado y no tengo ninguna queja en
that sense apart from there are people that I know
ese sentido aparte hay gente que conozco
there of those 30 people there were Well that
ahí ha de esas 30 personas habías Pues
eight or 10 that I knew then Ah it
eso ocho o 10 que conocía entonces Ah me
hurts me a lot I'm telling you those situations
duele mucho ya te digo esas situaciones
with animals Seeing the parrot that is there is that
con los animales Ver al al loro que está
no the parrot always bites me and
está que no el loro siempre me muerde y
now you're with the parrot There he is all
ahora estás con el lorito Ahí está todo
day on top Yesterday I made the video and he
el día encima Ayer hice el vídeo y
was all the time the bastard and and it
estaba todo el rato encima el cabrón y y
really is difficult it is difficult to happen but
realmente es [__] es [__] pasar pero
well that's what it is in the end what you're
bueno es lo que ha al final lo que ests
saying these days is that you don't have
diciendo estos días es que tú no tienes
any bad intentions nor are you a
ninguna mala intención ni eres ningún
criminal who was deceiving that he
delincuente que estuviera engañando que
was  well if you are doing something
estuviera pu si tú estás cometiendo algo
that you know is wrong you hide it, you
que tú sabes que está mal te esconde lo
cover it up and everyone has been
lo tapa y todo el mundo hemos estado
there seeing the animals we have done
allí viendo los animales hemos hecho
very viral live broadcasts and apart from that the whole
directos muy virales y aparte toda la
province knows you, they respect you for the
provincia te te conoce te respeta la
good relationship you have with all the
buena relación que tienes con toda la
neighbors of the land and so on not
gente de vecinos del terreno y demás no
everyone knew that you have the
todo el mundo sabía que tenes allí las
otters there everyone knows that
nutrias todo el mundo sabe que allí
the ostriches are there, that the
están las avestruces que existe la
savannah exists, that the camp exists. So it has
sabana que existe el campamento O sea
simply been in the end, well the
que ha sido simplemente al final pues
issue of paperwork is not a nonsense but
tema de papeleos no es una tontería pero
good that it is illegal and that's it, well that's what it is
que bueno que es ilegal y ya está pues
but also
es lo que hayy pero también también
Francis if nobody sends an email and they don't
Francis si nadie manda un email y no te
report you another 20 years go by the otters are
denuncian pasan otros 20 años las nutres
there and they came and they came two
ahí y vinieron y vinieron hace dos
weeks ago and nothing happened and nothing happened
semanas y no pasó nada y no pasó nada
exactly you know what happened that
exactamente sabes lo que pas que ya
well without taking out without taking out many
bueno sin sacar sin sacar muchas
predictions of what I know there is in in in
predicciones de lo se puede que ha en en
little thing no Let's see there are many
en poca cosa no A ver es que hay muchos
processes now with in the subject now on the
procesos ahora con en el tema ahora el
6th and the 12th I do not rule out that I
día 6 y el día 12 yo no descarto que yo
end up in jail for a while I
termine en la cárcel un tiempoo te lo
tell you like this for whatever for whatever
digo así por lo que sea por lo que sea
here let's see  Coincidences happen,
aquí sea a ver las casualidades pasan
but I've been in Thailand for 27 years, with
pero yo llevo 27 años en Tailandia con
all the good and bad things I've
todas las cosas buenas y malas que haya
done, with all the best and worst
hecho eh con todo lo mejor y peor
people I am, I've never had a
persona que sea yo jamás he tenido un
legal problem, never.
problema legal nunca